It is my pleasure to welcome Dr. Andrew Ng, tonight.
Andrew is the managing general partner of AI Fund,
founder of DeepLearning.AI and Landing AI,
chairman and co-founder of Coursera,
and an adjunct professor of Computer Science, here
at Stanford.
Previously, he had started and led the Google Brain
team, which had helped Google adopt modern AI.
And he was also director of the Stanford AI lab.
About eight million people, 1 in 1,000 persons on the planet,
have taken an AI class from him.
And through, both, his education and his AI work,
he has changed numerous lives.
Please welcome Dr. Andrew Ng.
[APPLAUSE]
Thank you, Lisa.
It's good to see everyone.
So, what I want to do today is chat to you
about some opportunities in AI.
So I've been saying AI is a new electricity.
One of the difficult things to understand about AI
is that it is a general purpose technology,
meaning that it's not useful only for one thing
but it's useful for lots of different applications,
kind of like electricity.
If I were to ask you, what is electricity good for?
It's not any one thing, it's a lot of things.
So what I'd like to do is start off sharing with you
how I view the technology landscape,
and this will lead into the set of opportunities.
So lot of hype, lot of excitement about AI.
And I think, a good way to think about AI
is as a collection of tools.
So this includes, a technique called supervised learning,
which is very good at recognizing things or labeling
things, and generative AI, which is a relatively new, exciting
development.
If you're familiar with AI, you may have heard of other tools.
But I'm going to talk less about these additional tools,
and I'll focus today on what I think are, currently,
the two most important tools, which are supervised learning
and generative AI.
So supervised learning is very good at labeling things
or very good at computing input to outputs or A to B
mappings, given an input A, give me an output.
For Example, given an email, we can use supervised
learning to label it as spam or not spam.
The most lucrative application of this
that I've ever worked on is probably online advertising,
where given an ad, we can label if a user
likely to click on it, and therefore,
show more relevant ads.
For self-driving cars, given the sensor readings of a car,
we can label it with where are the other cars.
One project, that my team, AI Fund, worked on
was ship route optimization.
Where given a route the ship is taking or considering taking,
we can label that with how much fuel
we think this will consume, and use this to make
ships more fuel efficient.
Did a lot of work in automated visual inspection in factories.
So you can take a picture of a smartphone, that
was just manufactured and label, is there a scratch
or any other defect in it.
Or if you want to build a restaurant review, reputation
monitoring system, you can have a little piece of software
that looks at online restaurant reviews,
and labels that as positive or negative sentiment.
So one nice thing, one cool thing about supervised learning
is that it's not useful for one thing, it's useful for all
of these different applications, and many more, besides.
Let me just walk through, concretely,
the workflow one example of a supervised learning,
labeling things kind of project.
If you want to build a system to label restaurant reviews,
you then collect a few data points or collect a data set.
Where it say, the pastrami sandwich great,
say that is positive.
Servers are slow, that's negative.
My favorite chicken curry, that's positive.
And here, I've shown three data points,
but you are building this, you may
get thousands of data points like this
or thousands of training examples, we call it.
And the workflow of a machine learning project, of an AI
project is, you get labeled data, maybe
thousands of data points.
Then you have an AI entry team train an AI
model to learn from this data.
And then finally, you would find,
maybe a cloud service to run the trained AI model.
And then you can feed it, best bubble tea I've ever had,
and that's positive sentiment.
And so, I think the last decade was maybe
the decade of large scale supervised learning.
What we found, starting about 10, 15 years ago
was if you were to train a small AI model,
so train a small neural network or small deep learning
algorithm, basically, a small AI model,
maybe not on a very powerful computer,
then as you fed it more data, its performance
would get better for a little bit
but then it would flatten out.
It would plateau, and it would stop
being able to use the data to get better and better.
But if you were to train a very large AI model, lots of compute
on maybe powerful GPUs, then as we scaled up the amount of data
we gave the machine learning model,
its performance would kind of keep
on getting better and better.
So this is why when I started and led the Google Brain
team, the primary mission that I directed the team to solve,
at the time, was let's just build really,
really large neural networks, that we then fed a lot of data
to.
And that recipe, fortunately, worked.
And I think the idea of driving large compute
and large scale of data, that recipe's really helped us,
driven a lot of AI progress over the last decade.
So if that was the last decade of AI,
I think this decade is turning out
to be also doing everything we had in supervised
learning but adding to it the exciting tool of generative AI.
So many of you, maybe all of you,
have played with ChatGPT and Bard, and so on.
But just given a piece of text, which you call a prompt,
like I love eating, if you run this multiple times,
maybe you get bagels cream cheese or my mother's meatloaf
or out with friends, and the AI system
can generate output like that.
Given the amounts of buzz and excitement about generative AI,
I thought I'd take just half a slide to say a little bit
about how this works.
So it turns out that generative AI, at least this type of text
generation, the core of it is using supervised
learning that inputs output mappings to repeatedly predict
the next word.
And so, if your system reads, on the internet,
a sentence like, my favorite food is a bagel with cream
cheese and lox, then this is translated into a few data
points, where if it sees, my favorite food is A,
in this case, try to guess that the right next word was bagel
or my favorite food is a bagel, try
to guess the next word is with, and similarly,
if it sees that, in this case, the right guess
for the next word would have been cream.
So by taking texts that you find on the internet
or other sources, and by using this input, output, supervised
learning to try to repeatedly predict the next word,
if you train a very large AI system on hundreds of billions
of words, or in the case of the largest models, now
more than a trillion words, then you get a large language model
like ChatGPT.
And there are additional, other important technical details.
I talked about predicting the next word.
Technically, these systems predict
the next subword or part of a word called a token,
and then there are other techniques like RLHF
for further tuning the AI output to be more helpful, honest,
and harmless.
But at the heart of it is this using supervised
learning to repeatedly predict the next word.
That's really what's enabling the exciting, really
fantastic progress on large language models.
So while many people have seen large language models
as a fantastic consumer tool.
You can go to a website like ChatGPT's website
or Bard's or other large language models
and use it as a fantastic tool.
There's one other trend, I think is still underappreciated,
which is the power of large language models,
not just as a consumer tool but as a developer tool.
So it turns out that there are applications
that used to take me months to build, that a lot of people
can now build much faster by using a large language model.
So specifically, the workflow for supervised learning,
building the restaurant review system,
say, would be that you need to get a bunch of labeled data,
and maybe that takes a month, we get a few thousand data points.
And then have an AI team train, and tune,
and really get optimized performance on your AI model.
Maybe that'll take three months.
Then find a cloud service to run it.
Make sure it's running robustly.
Make sure it's recognized, maybe that'll
take another three months.
So pretty realistic timeline for building a commercial grade
machine learning system is like 6 to 12 months.
And so teams I've led, we often took roughly 6 to 12 months
to build and deploy these systems.
And some of them turned out to be really valuable.
But this is a realistic timeline for building and deploying
a commercial grade AI system.
In contrast, with prompt-based AI, where you write a prompt.
This is what the workflow looks like.
You can specify a prompt, that takes maybe minutes or hours.
And then, you can deploy it to the cloud,
and that takes maybe hours or days.
So there are now certain AI applications
that used to take me, literally, six months,
maybe a year to build, that many teams around the world
can now build in maybe a week.
And I think this is already starting,
but the best is still yet to come.
This is starting to open up a flood of a lot more AI
applications that can be built by a lot of people.
So I think many people still underestimate
the magnitude of the flood of custom AI applications
that I think is going to come down the pipe.
Now, I know you probably were not
expecting me to write code in this presentation,
but that's what I'm going to do.
So it turns out, this is all the code
that I need in order to write a sentiment classifier.
So I'm going to--
some of you will know Python, I guess.
Import some tools from OpenAI, and then
add this prompt, that says, classify the text below
delimited by three dashes as having
either a positive or negative sentiment.
[INAUDIBLE],, I had a fantastic time at Stanford GSB.
Learnt a lot, and also made great new friends.
All right.
So that's my prompt.
And then I'm just going to run it.
And I've never run it before.
So I really hope--
thank goodness, it got the right answer.
[APPLAUSE]
And this is literally all the code
it takes to build a sentiment classifier.
And so, today, developers around the world
can take, literally, maybe 10 minutes
to build a system like this.
And that's a very exciting development.
So one of the things I've been working on
was trying to teach online classes about how
to use prompting, not just as a consumer
tool but as a developer too.
So just talking about the technology landscape,
let me now share my thoughts on what are some
of the AI opportunities I see.
This shows what I think is the value of different AI
technologies today, and I'll talk about three years
from now.
But the vast majority of financial value from AI today
is, I think, supervised learning,
where for a single company like Google
can be worth more than $100 billion US a year.
And also, there are millions of developers
building supervised learning applications.
So it's already massively valuable, and also
with tremendous momentum behind it just because
of the sheer effort in finding applications
and building applications.
And then, generative AI is the really exciting new entrant,
which is much smaller right now.
And then, there are the other tools
that I'm including for completeness.
If the size of these circles represent the value today,
this is what I think it might grow to in three years.
So supervised learning, already really massive,
may double, say, in the next three
years, from truly massive to even more massive.
And generative AI, which is much smaller today, I think,
will much more than double in the next three years because
of the number-- the amount of developer interest,
the amount of venture capital investments,
the number of large corporates exploring applications.
And I also just want to point out,
three years is a very short time horizon.
If it continues to compound in anything near this rate,
then in six years, it will be even vastly larger.
But this light shaded region in green or orange,
that light shaded region is where the opportunity is
for either new startups or for large companies, incumbents,
to create and to enjoy value capture.
But one thing I hope you take away from this slide
is that all of these technologies
are general purpose technologies.
So in the case of supervised learning,
a lot of the work that had to be done over the last decade,
but is continuing for the next decade,
is to identify and to execute on the concrete use cases.
And that process is also kicking off for generative AI.
So for this part of the presentation,
I hope you take away from it that general purpose technology
is a useful for many different tasks, lot of value
remains to be created using supervised learning.
And even though, we're nowhere near finishing figuring out
the exciting use cases of supervised learning,
we have this other fantastic tool of generative AI, which
further expands the set of things we can now do using AI.
But one caveat, which is that there will be
short term fads along the way.
So I don't know if some of you might
remember the app called Lensa.
This is the app that will let you
upload pictures of yourself, and then
will render a cool picture of you
as an astronaut or a scientist or something.
And it was a good idea and people liked it.
And its revenue just took off like crazy like that,
through last December.
And then it did that.
And that's because Lensa was-- it was a good idea.
People liked it.
But it was a relatively thin software layer
on top of someone else's really powerful APIs.
And so even though it was a useful product,
it was in a defensible business.
And when I think about apps like Lensa,
I'm actually reminded of when Steve Jobs gave us the iPhone.
Shortly after, someone wrote an app
that I paid $1.99 for, to do this, to turn on the LED,
to turn the phone into a flashlight.
And that was also a good idea to write an app
to turn on the LED light, but it also
wasn't a defensible long term--
also didn't create very long term value
because it was easily replicated, and underpriced,
and eventually incorporated into iOS.
But with the rise of iOS, with the rise of iPhone,
someone also figured out how to build things like Uber,
and Airbnb, and Tinder.
The very long term, very defensible businesses
that created sustaining value.
And I think, with the rise of generative AI
or the rise of new AI tools, I think, really,
what excites me is the opportunity
to create those really deep, really hard applications that
hopefully can create very long term value.
So the first trend I want to share
is AI is a general purpose technology.
And a lot of the work that lies ahead of us,
is to find the very diverse use cases and to build them.
There's a second trend I want to share
with you, which relates to why AI isn't more widely adopted
yet.
It feels like a bunch of us have been talking about AI
for 15 years or something.
But if you look at where the value of AI is today,
a lot of it is still very concentrated in consumer
software internet.
Once you got outside tech or consumer software internet,
there's some AI adoption but it all feels very early.
So why is that?
It turns out, if you were to take
all current and potential AI projects,
and sort them in decreasing order of value,
then to the left of this curve, of the head of this curve,
are the multi-billion dollar projects like advertising
or web search or for e-commerce product recommendations
or company like Amazon.
And it turns out that about 10, 15 years ago,
[? there's ?] my friends and I, we
figured out a recipe for how to hire, say,
100 engineers to write one piece of software
to serve more relevant ads, and apply that one
piece of software to a billion users,
and generate massive financial value.
So that works.
But once you go outside consumer software internet,
hardly anyone has 100 million or a billion users
that you can write and apply one piece of software to.
So once you go to other industries,
as we go from the head of this curve on the left
over to the long tail, these are some of the projects I see,
and I'm excited about.
I was working with a pizza maker that
was taking pictures of the pizza they were making because they
needed to do things like make sure that the cheese is spread
evenly.
So this is about a $5 million project.
But that recipe of hiring a hundred engineers or dozens
of engineers to work on a $5 million
project, that doesn't make sense.
Or there's another great example.
Working with a agriculture company
that with them, we figured out that if we use cameras
to find out how tall is the wheat,
and wheat is often bent over because
of wind or rain or something, and we
can chop off the wheat at the right height,
then that results in more food for the farmer to sell,
and is also better for the environment.
But this is another $5 million project,
that that old recipe of hiring a large group of highly
skilled engineers to work on this one project, that
doesn't make sense.
And similarly materials grading, cloth grading,
sheet metal grading, many projects like this.
So whereas to the left, in the head of this curve,
there's a small number of, let's say,
multi-billion dollar projects, and we
know how to execute those delivering value.
In other industries, I'm seeing a very long tail
of tens of thousands, of let's call them,
$5 million projects, that until now,
have been very difficult to execute on
because of the high cost of customization.
The trend that I think is exciting
is that the AI community has been building better tools that
lets us aggregate these use cases,
and make it easy for the end user to do the customization.
So specifically, I'm seeing a lot
of exciting low code and no code tools, that
enable the user to customize the AI system.
What this means is instead of me,
needing to worry that much about pictures of pizza,
we have tools--
we're starting to see tools that can enable
the IT department of the pizza making factory
to train AI system on their own pictures of pizza
to realize this $5 million worth of value.
And by the way, the pictures of pizza,
they don't exist on the internet.
So Google and Bing don't have access to these pictures,
we need tools that can be used by, really,
the pizza factory themselves, to build, and deploy,
and maintain their own custom AI system that works
on their own pictures of pizza.
And broadly, the technology for enabling this, some of it
is prompting, text prompting, visual prompting,
but really, large language models and similar tools
like that or a technology called data-centric AI, whereby,
instead of asking the pizza factory to write a lot of code,
which is challenging, we can ask them to provide data which
turns out to be more feasible.
And I think the second trend is important,
because I think this is a key part of the recipe for taking
the value of AI, which so far still feels
very concentrated in the tech world and the consumer software
internet world, and pushing this out to all industries, really
to the rest of the economy, which--
sometimes it's easy to forget, the rest of the economy
is much bigger than the tech world.
So the two trends I shared, AI as a general purpose
technology, lots of concrete use cases
to be realized as well as low code, no code, easy to use
tools, enabling AI to be deployed in more industries.
How do we go after these opportunities?
So about five years ago, there was a puzzle I wanted to solve,
which is--
I felt that many valuable AI projects are now possible.
And I was thinking, how do we get them done?
And having led teams in Google, and Baidu, in big tech
companies, I had a hard time figuring out
how I could operate a team in a big tech company
to go after a very diverse set of opportunities in everything
from maritime shipping to education to financial services
to healthcare, and on and on.
It's just very diverse use cases, very diverse
go to markets, and very diverse customer bases
and applications.
And I felt that the most efficient way
to do this would be if we can start
a lot of different companies to pursue these very
diverse opportunities.
So that's why I ended up starting AI Fund, which
is a venture studio that builds startups
to pursue a diverse set of AI opportunities.
And, of course, in addition to lots of startups,
incumbent companies also have a lot
of opportunities to integrate AI into existing businesses.
In fact, one pattern I'm seeing for incumbent businesses is
distribution is often one of the significant advantages
of incumbent companies, if they play their cards right,
can allow them to integrate AI into their products,
quite efficiently.
But just to be concrete, where are the opportunities?
So I think of this as-- this is what I think of as an AI stack.
At the bottom level is the hardware, semiconductor layer.
Fantastic opportunities there, but very capital intensive,
very concentrated.
So needs a lot of resources, relatively few winners.
So some people can and should play there.
I personally don't like to play there myself.
There's also the infrastructure layer.
Also fantastic opportunities, but very capital intensive,
very concentrated.
So I tend not to play there myself, either.
And then there's the developer tool layer.
What I showed you just now was--
I was actually using OpenAI's API as a developer tool.
And then, I think the developer tool
sector is a hypercompetitive.
Look at all the startups chasing OpenAI right now.
But there will be some mega winners.
And so I sometimes play here, but primarily,
when I think of a meaningful technology advantage,
because I think that earns you the right
or earns you a better shot at being one of the mega winners.
And then lastly, even though a lot of the media attention
and the buzz is in the infrastructure and developer
tooling layer, it turns out that layer can be successful
only if the application layer is even more successful.
And we saw this with the rise of SaaS as well.
Lot of the buzz and excitement is on the technology,
the tooling layer.
Which is fine.
Nothing wrong with that.
But the only way for that to be successful
is if the application layer is even more successful,
so that, frankly, they can generate
enough revenue to pay the infrastructure, and the tooling
layer.
So, actually, let me mention one example.
Amorai-- I was actually just texting the CEO yesterday.
But Amorai is a company that we built
that uses AI for romantic relationship coaching.
And just to point out, I'm an AI guy.
And I feel like I know nothing really about romance.
And if you don't believe me, you can ask my wife,
she will confirm that I know nothing about romance.
But when we went to build this, we
wanted to get together with the former CEO of Tinder, Renate
Nyborg.
And with my team's expertise in AI,
and her expertise in relationships
because she ran Tinder, she knows more about relationships
than I think anyone I know, we're
able to build something pretty unique using
AI for kind of romantic relationship mentoring.
And the interesting thing about applications like these
is when we look around, how many teams in the world
are simultaneously expert in AI and in relationships?
And so at the application layer, I'm
seeing a lot of exciting opportunities
that seem to have a very large market,
but where the competition sets is
very light, relative to the magnitude of the opportunity.
It's not that there are no competitors,
but it's just much less intense compared to the developer tool
or the infrastructure layers.
And so, because I've spent a lot of time iterating
on a process of building startups, what I'm going to do
is just, very transparently, tell
you the recipe we've developed for building startups.
And so after many years of iteration and improvement,
this is how we now build startups.
My team's always had access to a lot of different ideas,
internally generated, ideas from partners.
And I want to walk through this with one example of something
we did, which is a company Bearing AI,
which uses AI to make ships more fuel efficient.
So this idea came to me when, a few years ago,
a large Japanese conglomerate called Mitsui,
that is a major shareholder and operates major shipping lines,
they came to me and they said, hey, Andrew, you
should build a business to use AI to make ships more fuel
efficient.
And the specific idea was, think of it
as a Google Maps for ships.
We can suggest a ship or tell a ship how to steer,
so that you still get to your destination on time,
but using, it turns out, about 10% less fuel.
And so what we now do is we spend about a month,
validating the idea.
So double check, is this idea even technically feasible,
and then talk to prospective customers
to make sure there is a market need.
So we spent up to about a month doing that.
And if it passes this stage, then we
will go and recruit a CEO to work with us on the project.
When I was starting, out I used to spend
a long time working on a project myself,
before bringing on a CEO.
But after iterating, we realized that bringing
on a leader at the very beginning
to work with us, it reduces a lot of the burden of having
to transfer knowledge or having a CEO come in
and having to revalidate what [? we ?] discovered.
So the process is, we've, learned much more efficient,
we just bring the leader at the very start.
And so in the case of Bearing AI,
we found a fantastic CEO, Dylan Keil,
who is a reputed entrepreneur, one successful exit before.
And then we spent three months, six, two week sprints,
to work with them to build a prototype
as well as do deep customer validation.
If it survives this stage, and we
have about a two thirds, 66% survival rate,
we then write the first check in,
which then gives the company resources
to hire an executive team, build the key team,
get an MVP working, minimum viable product working,
and get some real customers.
And then after that, hopefully, then successfully
raises additional external rounds of funding,
and can keep on growing and scaling.
So I'm really proud of the work that my team
was able to do to support Mitsui's idea, and Dylan Keil,
as CEO.
And today, there are hundreds of ships, on the high seas
right now, that are steering themselves differently
because of Bearing AI.
And 10% fuel savings translates to around to maybe
$450,000 in savings in fuel, per, ship per year.
And, of course, it's also, frankly, quite a bit better
for the environment.
And I think this startup, I think,
would not have existed if not for Dylan's fantastic work,
and then also, Mitsui bringing this idea to me.
And I like this example because this is another one is like--
this is a startup idea that, just to point out,
I would never have come up with myself.
Because I've been on a boat but what
do I know about maritime shipping.
But is the deep subject matter expertise of Mitsui,
that had this insight, together with Dylan,
and then my team's expertise in AI, that made this possible.
And so as I operate in AI, one thing I've learned
is my swim lane is AI, and that's it.
Because I don't have time or it's very difficult for me
to be expert in maritime shipping,
and romantic relationships, and health care,
and financial services, and on, and on, and on.
And so I've learned that if I can just
help get a accurate technical validation,
and then use AI resources to make sure
the AI tech is built quickly and well,
and I think, we've always managed
to help the companies build a strong technical team,
then partnering with subject matter experts often results
in exciting new opportunities.
And I want to share with you one other weird aspect of--
one other weird thing I've learned
about building startups, which is I
like to engage only when there's a concrete idea.
And this runs counter to a lot of the advice you
hear from the design thinking methodology, which often says,
don't rush to solutioning.
Explore a lot of alternatives before you do a solution.
Honestly, we tried that, it was very slow.
But what we've learned is that at the ideation
stage, if someone comes to me and says, hey, Andrew,
you should apply AI to financial services.
Because I'm not a subject matter expert in financial services,
it's very slow for me to go and learn
enough about financial services, to figure out what to do.
I mean, eventually, you could get to a good outcome,
but it's a very labor intensive, very slow,
very expensive process, for me, to try to learn industry
after industry.
In contrast, one of my partners wrote this idea
as a tongue in cheek, not really seriously.
But, let's say, [INAUDIBLE] by GPT,
let's eliminate commercials by automatically
buying every product advertised in exchange for not having
to see any ads, it's not a good idea,
but it is a concrete idea.
And it turns out, concrete ideas can be validated or falsified,
efficiently.
They also give a team a clear direction to execute.
And I've learned that in today's world,
especially, with the excitement, the buzz, the exposure to AI
of a lot of people, it turns out that there
are a lot of subject matter experts in today's world,
that have deeply thought about a problem for months, sometimes
even one or two years.
But they've not yet had a build partner.
And when we get together with them, and hear,
and they share the idea of us, it
allows us to work with them to very quickly go
into validation and building.
And I find that this works because there
are a lot of people that have already done the design
thinking thing of exploring a lot of ideas and winnowing
down to really good ideas.
And there are-- I find that there are so
many good ideas sitting out there,
that no one is working on.
That finding those good ideas that someone has already
had, and wants to share with us, and wants to build partner for,
that turns out to be a much more efficient engine.
So before I wrap up, we'll go to the question in a second,
just a few slides to talk about risk and social impact.
So AI is very powerful technology.
To say something you'd probably guess, my teams and I,
we only work on projects that move humanity forward.
And we have multiple times killed projects
that we assess to be financially sound, based
on ethical grounds.
It turns out, I've been surprised
and sometimes dismayed at the creativity of people
to come up with good ideas.
So to come up with really bad ideas that
seem profitable but really should not be built.
We've killed a few projects on those grounds.
And then, I think, has to be acknowledged that AI today
does have problems with bias, fairness, and accuracy.
But also the technology is improving quickly.
So I see that AI systems today are
less biased than six months ago, and more
fair than six months ago, which is not
to dismiss the importance of these problems.
They are problems and we should continue to work on them.
But I'm also gratified at the number
of teams working hard on these issues
to make them much better.
When I think of the biggest risks of AI.
I think that the biggest risks--
one of the biggest risks is the disruption to jobs.
This is a diagram from a paper by our friend at the University
of Pennsylvania, and some folks at OpenAI,
analyzing the exposure of different jobs
to AI automation.
And it turns out that, whereas, the previous wave of automation
mainly--
the most exposed jobs were often the lower wage jobs,
such as when we put robots into factories.
With this current wave of automation,
is actually the higher wage jobs, further,
to the right of this axis, that seems
to have more of their tasks exposed to automation.
So even as we create tremendous value using AI,
I feel like, as citizens, and our corporations,
and our governments, and, really,
our society, I feel a strong obligation
to make sure that people, especially people whose
livelihoods are disrupted, are still well taken care of,
are still treated well.
And then lastly, there's also been--
it feels like every time there's a big wave of progress in AI,
there's a big wave of hype about artificial general intelligence
as well.
When DeepLearning started work really well 10 years ago,
there was a lot of hype about AGI.
And now, the generative AI is working really well,
there's another wave of hype about AGI.
But I think that artificial general intelligence,
AI that can do anything a human can do
is still decades away, maybe 30 to 50 years, maybe even longer.
I hope we'll see it in our lifetimes.
But I don't think there's any time soon.
One of the challenges is that the biological path
to intelligence, like humans and the digital path
to intelligence, AI, they've taken very different paths.
And the funny thing about the definition of AGI
is you're benchmarking this very different digital path
to intelligence with really the biological path
to intelligence.
So I think, large language models are smarter
than any of us in certain key dimensions,
but much dumber than any of us in other dimensions.
And so forcing it to do everything a human can do
is like a funny comparison.
But I hope we'll get there.
Hopefully, within our lifetimes.
And then there's also a lot of, I think,
overblown hype about AI creating extinction risks for humanity.
Candidly, I don't see it.
I just don't see how AI creates any meaningful extinction
risk for humanity.
I think that people worry we can't control AI.
But we have lots of, AI will be more powerful than any person.
But with lots of experience, steering, very powerful
entities, such as corporations or nation states that
are far more powerful than any single person,
and making sure they, for the most part, benefit humanity.
And also technology develops gradually.
The so-called hot take off scenario,
where it's not really working today,
and then suddenly, one day, overnight,
it works brilliantly, and we achieve super intelligence,
takes over the world.
That's just not realistic.
And I think the AI technology will develop slowly,
like all the--
and then it gives us plenty of time
to make sure that we provide oversight and can
manage it to be safe.
And lastly, if you look at the real extinction risk
to humanity, such as, fingers crossed,
the next pandemic or climate change,
leading to a massive de-population of some parts
of the planet, or much lower odds, but maybe someday,
an asteroid doing to us what it had done to the dinosaurs.
I think if we look at the actual real extinction
risk to humanity, AI having more intelligence,
even artificial intelligence in the world,
would be a key part of the solution.
So I feel like if you want humanity to survive and thrive
for the next 1,000 years, rather than slowing AI down,
which some people propose, I would rather
make AI go as fast as possible.
So with that, just to summarize, this is my last slide.
I think that AI, as a general purpose technology
creates a lot of new opportunities for everyone.
And a lot of the exciting and important work that
lies ahead of us all is to go and build those concrete use
cases, and hopefully, in the future,
hopefully, I'll have opportunities to maybe
engage with more of you on those opportunities as well.
So with that, let me just say, thank you all very much.
[APPLAUSE]